Peter Yoon

TL;DR

I have an unconventional path to becoming a product manager.

Analogous to systems thinking, I have experience in many constituent positive reinforcing roles that interrelate and holistically support the context of an overarching role. My curiosities have driven me to be a teacher, program manager, startup founder, marketer, developer, and technical project manager. I have found success in each role.

I like to embody the principles of collaboration, empowerment, radical candor, delivering value, being flexible to adapt to changes, and reflecting on and improving processes. I'm looking forward to learning more about the needs of REI and how I can provide value.

I enjoy starting my mornings by meditating and drinking tea. I like to bring calm energy and an open-minded attitude into my daily experiences and hope to share that with my coworkers.

You can find more of my musing at https://peteryyoon.com. I recently launched a hobby site at https://otio.world.

Peter Young Jun Yoon

I am a results-driven and self-motivated PM with extensive experience scaling global businesses. I aspire to facilitate high-impact projects by accurately identifying needs, shaping solutions, effectively communicating between stakeholders, and balancing expectations.

RECENT EXPERIENCE

Opal Labs, PDX — Technical Project Manager

Feb 2021 - Present

Maintaining smooth process frameworks while evolving steps to balance the needs and challenges of an organization pushing for growth.

- Successfully managed 9-12 projects within any given sprint adhering to Agile principles.
- Identified engineering pain points, pitched, reorganized, and transitioned the engineering team from a sizeable 15-member group to 2 pods to improve communication, scale development, and improve Scrum/Agile processes.
- Improved forecasting and project resourcing by introducing Monte Carlo simulation forecasting to generate early-stage project timelines using historical developer throughput.
- Increased the accuracy of project completion forecasting by creating a sprint point forecasting model to help teams effectively commit to points, keep morale high, and accurately hit end dates.
- Created and scaled cross-functional processes for new integrations across Engineering, Product, GTM, and Customer stakeholders. Essentially, organized internal feature demos, customer onboarding email and information collection templates, project intake processes, and customer testing steps.

Travel & Continuing Education [See EDUCATION]

Aug 2019 - Feb 2020

Uber Technologies, SF — Senior Manager, ASO Program Jun 2018 - Aug 2019

Managed and operationalized Uber's ASO team and leveraged data for insights to optimize Uber's app stores on a global scale continually.

- Built a testing model and generated +\$80M in annualized ad spend savings globally from H1 2018 to H1 2019.
- Increased testing velocity by 40% YOY by managing a team and partnering with contact points in LATAM, EMEA, and APAC.
- Proposed and democratized data recording and analysis practices by restructuring data-keeping methodologies that adhere to Tidy Data's best practices.
- Collaborated with Marketing Analytics to build a comprehensive program dashboard based on the needs and requirements of senior leadership.

M&C Saatchi Performance, NYC — Senior Strategist, Program Manager Dec 2016 - Jun 2018

Built a new program around a growing marketing niche, performed market due diligence, determined pricing structures, and built processes/frameworks with cutting-edge marketing tools.

- On-boarded six ASO clients within two guarters.
- Increased store listing conversion rates by up to 30% for six clients.
- Collaborated with the in-house programming team to build innovative and proprietary marketing tools used department-wide.
- Planned, conducted, and controlled all procurement and managed cost, time, and quality for all clients.

LinkedIn Portfolio GitHub

Lake Oswego, OR (224) 770-0478 peteryyoon@gmail.com

EARLY EXPERIENCE

M&C Saatchi Performance Strategist, Project Manager

Chungdahm Learning Instructor, PM, Content Creator

PMON, Inc. Co-Founder

SKILLS

PMI Certified, Data-Driven PM, Agile, Jira, Google Suite

RESTful API Design, Full Stack Development, Version Control

LANGUAGES, FRAMEWORKS, DATABASES, & MISC.

Javascript, React, Express, Knex, Node.js, Postgres, CSS

Git, Docker, Heroku

EDUCATION

Thinkful Remote

Engineering Flex Program

University of Michigan Ann Arbor BS Biology

SPEAKING AND WRITING

ASO Stack, Ad Week, ASO Stack, Ad Exchanger, TWiST